Alexander (Sasha) Weiss

© Evanston, IL +17738967224 ☐ sasha@sashaweiss.coffee

Software Engineering Intern - Braintree

Summary

I'm an incoming Master's student in Computer Science at Northwestern University, with significant industry and academic research experience. My past work and interests have centered on autonomous and productivity technologies - software that makes stuff easier, for *people*. I speak French in addition to English, and I love ballet and Star Wars!

Work experience

Software Engineering Intern

June 2017 - present

Braintree Payments

• Building developer-facing SDKs for easy payment processing. Focusing on developing code generation to streamline updates and maintenance of SDKs spanning 6+ server-side languages.

Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 - Sep 2016

HERE Maps (formerly NAVTEQ)

• Built and deployed a Scala library supporting custom indexing into map datastores. Reduced processing time of my team's products by between ~2 and ~50x.

Undergraduate Researcher

Winter 2016 - present

Delta Lab, Northwestern University

- Running an independent research project to investigate how mobile context-sensing and microreminding techniques can support long-term behavior change, such as habit-building.
- Built an iOS prototype reminder system and deployed for ~1 month. Currently preparing a conference submission from gathered data.

Teaching Assistant

Winter 2016 - present

Northwestern University

• Lead tutorial sessions and host office hours for introductory CS courses, teaching in C++, Python, and Racket.

Education

Combined BS/MS in Computer Science

Sep 2014 - June 2018

Northwestern University McCormick School of Engineering GPA: 3.89/4.00

Lan	gua	ges
TOTAL	700	700

Proficient

Swift (iOS), Typescript, Python

Working

C++, Bash, C, Node.js, Scala, Racket, Docker, Gradle, MATLAB